

+86 156-0165-4544 drew.xiu@gmail.com https://github.com/noru

OVERVIEW

5 years programming experience in a wide range of technical stacks. Strong learning ability and willingness. Team player and efficient communicator, always took a role as key developer in team. Tech nerd and enthusiastic about efficiency and quality. Full stack web developer since beginning, and now an experienced front-end engineer. Looking forward to sharpen my skills and acquire new ones.

EXPERIENCE

General Electric; Healthcare Digital China, Front-end Engineer — 2017.4 - now

- Be front-end specialist in Asset Management product team. Leading technical discussion and decision in the team.
- Data visualization development, such as reports, dashboards. With UX team, implement modern, attractive final UI or reusable components.
- Constantly evolve the project: migrate features from traditional SSR pages to a SPA/micro service architecture; Combine scattered repos, unify technical stack to create a scalable front-end project and improve productivity. Integrate & customize 3rd party components like BI tools.
- Be an early adopter of new techs in the team, learn with actions and spread the result to the other team members.
- Interviewing front-end engineer for both Shanghai/Beijing team.
- Tech stack: typescript/react + react-*/antd/echarts

Autodesk China R&D; Cloud Platform; Software Engineer — 2014.8 - 2017.4

- Working on a RESTful API for Autodesk Revit/Fusion to manage/render materials. Based on asp.net. Built a browser based admin console, using Vuejs.
- Full stack developer of https://apps.autodesk.com. AppStore is a platform built for 3rd party developers or firms to share/sell their plugins. Based on asp.net, with jQuery and angular. Back-end is written in Scala/ Play with MySQL. I'm the sole developer of back-end REST api and involved in most front-end development.

SAP Labs China; Globalization Service; Developer — 2012-2014

Developer of ERP Financial modules and their globalized version. Experienced ABAPer and lead team to deliver 3 Fiori(UI5) Apps. ABAP is SAP's own programming language and Fiori(UI5) is an enterprise Html5 framework.

Autodesk China R&D; Localization Testing; Intern — 2010-2012

Conduct automation testing for Autodesk hero products, develop necessary tools, many of them are using Python. Best Intern Award of 2011.

WORTH-SAYINGS

Android native apps, Node.js, CICD pipeline(Jenkins, Docker) experience.

EDUCATION

NWPU — Bachelor of Aerodynamics, 2009; Fudan University — Aerodynamics, 2012, complete of course

SKILLS

OOP, FP, JavaScript stack, React stack, Scala, C#, Android/Java, AWS, Git, REST, SQL, Non-SQL

+86 156-0165-4544 drew.xiu@gmail.com https://github.com/noru

概况

5+年软件开发经验,项目经历包含ERP和Web前后端。对中小型网站和服务的技术栈有较为全面的了解和上手经验。目前更专注于Web前端开发,对前端单页应用和数据可视化方面深入的实践。

经历

通用电气Healthcare Digital, Front-end Engineer 2017.4 - 至今

- 团队的产品为资产管理及相关功能平台。团队中专注前端相关的工作,参与前端技术架构的讨论和决策。 为团队提供前端相关的咨询。
- 负责产品可视化部分(报表,看板等)的开发。实现设计团队的方案,为用户提供有吸引力的前端界面和交互。以及整合第三方工具到我们的产品, 如BI报表工具。
- 持续改进和重构项目。包括JSP旧页面到新架构的无缝迁移(单页应用+微服务);整合分散的前端工程,统一技术栈,减少维护和学习成本,并最终实现项目repo的可扩展性。
- 率先学习和应用新的技术到已有项目中,为同事分享学习经验。
- 上海/北京团队的前端工程师的面试工作。
- 技术栈: typescript/react and react-*/antd/echarts

Autodesk中国软件研发研究院; Cloud Platform; Software Engineer 2014.8 - 现在

- 为公司其他产品提供关于材质主数据及渲染图管理的相关REST Api, 基于asp.net. 前端控制台Web界面为单页应用, 使用Vue.js
- https://apps.autodesk.com的前后端开发. AppStore是Autodesk第三方插件发布与销售平台. 基于asp.net, 前端有使用jQuery和angular. 后端Scala/Play + MySQL提供REST Api. 参与了绝大部分前端的开发, 独立完成所有的后端开发. 部署于AWS.

SAP中国研究院; Globalization Service; Developer 2012-2014

ERP系统FI(财务)模块本地化产品的开发与维护. 使用ABAP提供REST Api, UI5作为前端框架. ABAP是SAP的ERP系统使用的语言, UI5是SAP的企业级Html5框架,主要基于jQuery.

Autodesk中国软件研发研究院; 本地化测试部門; Intern; 2010-2012

Autodesk产品的自动化测试, 以及测试工具的开发, 其中测试脚本以及很多工具类脚本使用的Python. 2011年Best Intern Award.

其他

有Android, Node.js的经验. 熟悉基本的CICD(Jenkins, Docker)的架构流程.

教育

西北工业大学 飞行器设计与工程,2009;复旦大学 飞行器设计与工程,2012

技能

OOP, FP, JavaScript stack, React stack, Scala, C#, Android/Java, AWS, Git, REST, SQL, Non-SQL